Jeff Liang

Authorized to work in the United States Willing to relocate

Phone: (626)456-2859

Email: jeff.c.liang@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-c-liang

Website: www.jeffliang.us

A software engineer who is currently working at a subsidiary of AT&T called Fullscreen, where primarily working on internal tools using Javascript. 3 years of experience building web applications in JavaScript/TypeScript (React, Redux), HTML5, and CSS3. Looking for a full-stack developer opportunity.

SKILLS

- ◆ JavaScript/ES6 (TypeScript, React, Redux, Jest) ◆ CSS3 (Sass, Bootstrap) ◆ HTML5 ◆ Ruby on Rails
- ◆ Python ◆ Git ◆ Jest ◆ AVA ◆ Cypress ◆ AWS ECS/Codepipeline ◆ 2D/3D CAD design, Catia

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer- Fullscreen, Los Angeles, CA

Aug 2019 - Present

FS Connect | Ruby on rails, React-Rails, Bootstrap

Create a credential management tool to enable the data engineering team to retrieve YouTube analytics data via the Reporting API.

- Built forms, sortable tables for CRUD operations and use React-Rails for state management on modal, table editing, toggle buttons, etc.
- Be able to tackle backend tickets such as updated controller method to get filtered channel data and added model method to get human-readable connection type.
- Customized UI systematically by updating bootstrap variables instead of adding one-off styling. And provided technical advice to designers for UI/UX design.
- Generated test cases, updated dummy users' channels status to validate table row onClick events and alert messages under different scenarios.

♦ HUB | React, Redux, AVA/Cypress, Storybook

Implement features on an existing internal tool for influencer managers to create action items, track talents' earnings, payments, and channel detail.

- Provided backend engineers APIs requirements to get categorized YouTube earnings information, and hook APIs on the frontend.
- Built dashboards, fixed columns and expandable rows on the talent earnings table with categorized earnings data to improve the **data visualization**.
- Applied TDD by writing unit tests, component tests in AVA and end to end tests in Cypress.
- Added Storybook style guide to standardized UI implementation.
- Refactored code by creating reusable functions for similar blocks of code and reducing code complexity.
 Improved remediation grade from F to B on Code Climate.

Software Engineer - KLA, San Jose, CA

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Unified Issue Tracker | TypeScript, React(hooks), Sharepoint API

- Integrated product issue data from 3 different sources to Sharepoint List to reduce SAP server loading.
- implemented main toggle button to select/unselect all tasks in different tables and sub-toggle buttons to select/unselect tasks in the individual table.
- Used React hooks for UI components state management and shared the uptodate framework knowledge with the team.

EDUCATION

App Academy Full stack web development bootcamp Wright State University MS - Mechanical Engineering

Feb 2018 - May 2018 Class of 2016